🔥 Enjoy massive savings with our [Black Friday Sale!](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/black-friday) 🔥

Browse

 Search 

* Batteries
    
    * Alkaline Batteries

    * Rechargeable Batteries

    * Lithium Batteries

    * Coin Cell Batteries

    * Specialist Batteries

    * Battery Accessories

    * Shop by Use

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* Cables & Adapters
    
    * USB-C

    * USB-A

    * Lightning (iPhone)

    * HDMI

    * Monitor

    * Television

    * Audio

    * Power

    * Networking

    * Tech Kits

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* Computing & Mobile
    
    * Chargers

    * PC & Laptop

    * Phone & Tablet

    * Networking

    * Tech Kits

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More
        
        * [What is the difference between HDMI splitters & HDMI switches?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/difference-between-hdmi-splitters-switches)

* Photo & Video
    
    * Photo

    * Video

    * Optics

    * Accessories

    * Shop by Use

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* TV, Audio & Stage
    
    * Headphones

    * Microphones

    * Stage & Studio

    * Speakers

    * TV Brackets & Trolleys

    * Tech Kits

    * Shop by Use

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* Electricals & Lighting
    
    * Solar Power

    * Electrical Supplies

    * Smart Bulbs

    * Indoor Lighting

    * Outdoor Lighting

    * Portable Lighting

    * Lighting Accessories

    * Heating & Cooling

    * Security

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* Car
    
    * Car Maintenance

    * Car Accessories

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* Furniture & Storage
    
    * Desks

    * Chairs

    * Brackets & Mounts

    * Flight Cases

    * Tech Kits

    * Home Office Bundles

    * Shop by Brand

    * Learn More

* Components & Tools
    
    * Cable & Wire

    * Cable Management

    * Connectors

    * Electrical & Power

    * Electro Mechanical

    * Enclosures

    * Industrial

    * Maker Space

    * Optoelectronics

    * Passives

    * Semiconductors

    * Tools & Equipment

* Black Friday
    
    * Fujifilm Deals

    * Photography & Imaging Deals

    * Stage & Audio Deals

    * Home & Office Deals

    * Everyday Deals

    * Other Deals

 Search 

 Search 

    #### [What are the different battery sizes and types?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/battery-sizes-and-types)
    
    If you’re baffled by batteries and stumped by sizes, we’ve put together a handy guide to help you find what you’re looking for at Maplin!

    * 

    #### [Confused about cables?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/confused-about-cable-types)
    
    A cable is just a cable, right? Well, it isn’t quite that simple. There are all sorts of features and tech details that are important to understand to make sure you get the ideal cable for your needs.

    * 

    #### [Why use a USB hub?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/why-use-a-usb-hub)
    
    Whether you’re using a laptop with limited ports or you need to connect a device but don’t have the right connection available, USB hubs can solve all your problems! Available in both USB-A and USB-C varieties, USB hubs often feature multiple connectivity options, but which one is right for you?

    * 
    * [What is the difference between HDMI splitters & HDMI switches?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/difference-between-hdmi-splitters-switches)

    #### [What are portable photo printers?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/what-are-portable-photo-printers)
    
    If you’re tired of just admiring your favourite photos on your phone screen, a portable photo printer can help you create a physical keepsake of those special moments. But what exactly is a photo printer? And how does it connect to your smartphone?

    * 

    #### [What are the different types of microphones?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/different-types-of-microphones)
    
    Whether you need professional sound quality for a business call or you’re taking to the stage to perform, you’ll need a microphone to make sure your voice is heard. But which model is right for you?

    * 

    #### [What are power stations?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/what-is-a-power-station)
    
    You’ve probably heard of power banks – handy portable power units, ideal for keeping your phone, headphones and other electronic devices charged up while you’re on the go. But what exactly is a power station?

    * 

    #### [Understanding EV Charging Cables In The UK](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/understanding-ev-charging-cables-in-the-uk)
    
    Electric vehicles (EVs) are gaining popularity around the world, including in the United Kingdom. As more people switch to EVs, the need for reliable and efficient charging solutions becomes paramount.

    * 

    #### [Which chair is best for my home or office space?](https://www.maplin.co.uk/blogs/expert-advice/which-chair-is-best-for-home-office)
    
    From protecting your posture to adding style to your setup, it’s important to choose the right chair for your needs. At Maplin we offer a wide range, so read on to find the ideal match for your home or office space.

    * 

[

Batteries](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/batteries)[

Cables & Adapters](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/cables-adapters)[

Computing & Mobile](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/computing-mobile)[

Photo & Video](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/photo-video)[

TV, Audio & Stage](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/tv-audio-stage)[

Electricals & Lighting](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/electricals-lighting)[

Car](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/car)[

Furniture & Storage](https://www.maplin.co.uk/pages/furniture-storage)

Privacy policy
==============

**Our promises**

We are Digital-First Retail Limited ("we", "our", "us") and operate under the name of Maplin.

We're 100% committed to keeping your data safe and secure. Our Maplin team are avid online shoppers, so we totally appreciate and respect how important privacy is. If you have any worries about your personal information feel free to reach out through [online chat](https://maplin-customer-support.gorgias.help/en-US/contact) or email [help@maplin.co.uk](mailto:help@maplin.co.uk), we'd be happy to answer any questions you have!

**Why we need your information**

There may be times when you give us 'sensitive' information and we protect this data like it's our own. We only ask for the essentials and we use your data to provide you the best service possible. The table below shows why we need this information:

| #### Your Details | #### Why? |
| --- | --- |
| Name, Address & Phone Number | * Order Updates<br>* Delivery<br>* Fraud Prevention<br>* After Sales Support |
| Date of Birth & Gender | Fraud Prevention |
| Payment Information | * Payment<br>* Refunds<br>* Fraud Prevention |
| Purchase History & Saved Items | * Refunds<br>* After Sales Support<br>* Personalise your shopping experience<br>* Recommend products we think you'd like |
| IP Address & Device Type | * Fraud Prevention<br>* Website and service improvments<br>* Personalise your shopping experience |

**  
Who we share your information with**

Your trust means everything to us, so we will only share your personal data with a selection of our most trusted partners.

These companies include:

* Search Engines and Analytics providers
* Affiliate Partners
* Fulfilment Partners
* Digital-First Retail Group Companies and Partners
* Anyone who you give us permission to share your info with

We partner with selected third-party vendors, such as [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en), and others, to allow tracking technologies and remarketing services on the Site through the use of first party cookies and third-party cookies, to, among other things, analyse and track users’ use of the Site, determine the popularity of certain content and better understand online activity. By accessing the Site, you consent to the collection and use of your information by these third-party vendors. You are encouraged to review their privacy policy and contact them directly for responses to your questions. We do not transfer personal information to these third-party vendors. However, if you do not want any information to be collected and used by tracking technologies, you can visit the third-party vendor or the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out Tool](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) or [Digital Advertising Alliance Opt-Out Tool](https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN).

For the purpose of:

* Website Performance Analytics
* Processing your orders - payment providers & couriers
* Customer support - online chat, reviews & installation suppliers
* Tackling fraud - cyber security & law enforcement agencies
* Website hosts & maintenance

We would like to specifically draw your attention to the fact that we share certain personal information with third parties who help us to detect and prevent fraudulent transactions. The information we share with those third parties includes some of the information that you share with us (such as, your contact details and information about the transaction), and some of the information from your online interactions (such as the IP address of your device). That information is used to determine whether a transaction could be fraudulent. The third party we currently use to help us detect and prevent fraudulent transactions is a company called Signifyd; they are responsible for their use of your personal information and will use it for the purposes set out in their privacy policy (https://www.signifyd.com/privacy/).

Finally, we'll also share your information to comply with the law, to enforce our Terms and Conditions and protect the rights, property and safety of the Maplin team, our customers and others.

**How long we hold onto your data for**

We'll only keep your information on file for as long as you are a customer. If you haven't logged onto our website for three years we will delete your information from our systems. If you no longer wish to be a customer, you can also contact our support team and request to delete all the information we have on you.

In some circumstances, like cases of anti-money laundering or fraud, we may keep data longer if we need to or the law says we have to.

**Marketing**

If you have opted in to our marketing messages you'll receive updates by email and text on product launches and promotions.

No longer want to receive updates from us? No problem, you can stop our marketing by signing into your account on our website and clicking 'Your Details' and 'No, don't sign me up'. Alternatively email our support team at [help@maplin.co.uk](mailto:help@maplin.co.uk) and we'll update your preferences.

Please bare in mind that Maplin has many inter-connecting services so it may take a few days for our systems to update. Also stopping marketing messages will not stop order related updates.

**Your rights**

You have a right to:

* Access the personal data we hold about you
* Be informed about how your personal data is being used
* Update incorrect data we have on file
* Request to delete your information on file
* Stop all direct marketing communication
* Complain to your data protection regulator (ICO)

**Feedback - good or bad! ✔✖**

If you simply need us to explain anything mentioned above or you're concerned about your personal data please reach out to us by email [help@maplin.co.uk](mailto:help@maplin.co.uk).

**Changes to this policy**

We'll post any changes we make to our privacy notice on this page and if they're significant changes we'll post it on the Maplin website and let you know by email.

#### UK Trusted Brand

Your electronics specialist since 1972

#### Free UK Shipping

On most items when you spend over £35

#### Easy Returns

Our returns portal makes things quick & easy

#### Support

Our friendly support team is here to help

##### Expert Advice

##### Shopping With Us

##### Help & Information

##### Company

##### Newsletter

Be the first to hear about our latest offers, promotions and expert advice.

Please enter your email

_By submitting you agree to our_ [_Privacy Policy_](https://www.maplin.co.uk/policies/privacy-policy "Privacy Policy")

© 2024 Digital-First Retail Ltd, All rights reserved.  
Maplin & MPS are registered trademarks of OYOD Holdings Ltd.

Payment methods

* American Express
* Apple Pay
* Diners Club
* Discover
* Google Pay
* Maestro
* Mastercard
* PayPal
* Shop Pay
* Union Pay
* Visa

* Choosing a selection results in a full page refresh.
